

# **OBJECTIVES**

I would like to work as a Software Engineer and put my accumulated expertise from numerous projects and courses over the last few years to use. I am looking forward to contributing and as well as learning new technologies from time to time.

+88015-2143-1502

🔀 shahariaresha@gmail.com

Abdullah Esha

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor Of Science in Computer Science and Engineering (2018– 2021)

American International University - Of Bangladesh

Higher Secondary School Certificate (2015–2017)

BAF Shaheen College, Dhaka 1206

#### **CERTIFICATES**

# Crash Course on Python (Jul 2020)

An online non-credit course authorized by Google and offered through Coursera.

#### CyberOps Associate (Dec 2021)

An online course authorized by CISCO and offered by AIUB.

Paper: Assisting the Power Generation Sector Toward Sustainability-an IoT Based... (March 2022)

Apaper published on ACM Digital Libary

# ABDULLAH **ESHA**

# Software Engineer

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Swop Technologies (May 2022 - Present)

#### Full-Stack Web Developer

I began with React JS and Laravel-based projects, transitioned to Next JS with an Express JS backend, and excelled in delivering complex, client-specific functionalities. Additionally, I managed deployments on AWS (EC2) and worked with cPanel for hosting tasks.

# Atropos (Sep 2021 - Dec 2021)

# Internship

I completed small learning projects using HTML5, CSS3, and PHP, gaining valuable experience in web development

#### **CORE SKILLS**

#### **Programming Language**

JavaScript, Typescript

#### **Frameworks**

Express.js, Next js

#### Web Technologies

Tailwind CSS, JWT, Firebase Auth, React js, Redux, RTK, jQuery and RESTful API

#### **SQL** and Database

MySQL, MongoDB

#### Project deployment and version control

GitHub, Git Bash, cPanel, AWS(EC2)

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

C, C++,Java, C#, Python

Laravel, .NET (MVC)

HTML5, CSS3, MUI, jQuery, Ajax, JSON

Oracle, MSSQL

Docker, Jenkins

Ether JS\*, Web3\* (Familiarity with)

Linux (Security Onion, Ubuntu), Postman

Trello, GitLab

#### **AWARDS**

#### Dean's Award (2018)

American International University of Bangladesh.

# **LANGUAGES**

- English
- Bengali

# **INTERESTS**

- Playing Football
- Reading Books

#### REFERENCES

#### **RAIHAN UDDIN AHMED**

Assistant Professor
Department of Computer Science.
ruabng2008@gmail.com
American International University
Bangladesh.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Butterfly Matrimonial V2.0 (Jul 2022 - Aug 2022)

React JS, Redux, Laravel 9, MySql

A digital matchmaking platform designed for Butterfly Matrimonial. Its primary aim is to collect comprehensive bio-data from individuals, enhancing the matchmaking process. This data forms the basis for advanced analytical and sorting tools featured on this platform, offering a sophisticated and efficient matchmaking experience.

#### SWOP V2.0 (Mar 2023 - Jun 2023)

Next JS, Express JS, MongoDB, Stripe

An e-commerce website has been developed to facilitate the sale and purchase of NFC chips. The website utilizes SendGrid to send automated emails to users for order confirmation, forgot passwords, subscriber alerts, and other purposes. Stripe has been integrated to enable secure and seamless payment processing. JWT authentication is implemented to ensure user safety and data protection. Additionally, the website provides a comprehensive dashboard with analytical features to assist users in tracking their transactions and performance.

#### Bayshor Communication V3.0 (Feb 2023)

Next JS, Typescript

This project was the first professional experience to utilize TypeScript and Next.js 13.5 (app router). It was developed as a complete marketing and software solution agency website, specifically using predefined JSON data to facilitate integration with the backend and provide dashboard control.

#### Halal kabab & Curry (Apr 2023)

Next js, MongoDB, useContext, Google Map API

This project seamlessly integrates essential features such as payment processing through PayPal, location services via Google Maps, and email communication facilitated by SendGrid, to streamline and enhance the operational efficiency of these establishments. Bearer token used to authenticate admin API.

#### Nazaara (Jun 2023 - Present)

Next js, Express js, Typescript, MongoDB, Firebase

An e-commerce website especially for women's wear. Contents are fully customizable (text, image) from the dashboard. Already had a solution for outlet management and that project connected with the web-based solution through API. SendGrid has been implemented to send emails to users, features like order confirmation, forgot password, subscriber alert, etc. Payment API SSLCommerz applied for transection's additionally that payment service has partial payment features. JWT authentication and other analytical features are provided on the dashboard and the main website. Still working on some key features.